Guide to the Oregonian photographs collection circa 1850-1984
Oregon Historical Society, Research Library
- Oregon, circa 1900-1984; Series B
  - Cleawox Lake (Box-folder 18/39)
    See also: Oregon - Honeyman State Park.
  - Clifton (Box-folder 19/1)
  - Cold Spur Camp (Box-folder 19/2)
  - Collier State Park (Box-folder 19/3)
  - Colton (Box-folder 19/4)
  - Columbia County (Box-folder 19/5)
  - Columbia Gorge Arts Festival (Box-folder 19/6)
  - Columbia Region Information Sharing System (CRISS) (Box-folder 19/7)
  - Columbia River and Gorge (1) (Box-folder 19/8)
  - Columbia River and Gorge (2) (Box-folder 19/9)
  - Columbia River Improvement Proposals (Box-folder 19/10)
  - Columbia River Jetties and Levees (Box-folder 19/11)
    Includes photographs of jetties at the Columbia's mouth in Astoria.
  - Columbia River Wave Study, 1980 (Box-folder 19/12)
  - Concord (Box-folder 19/13)
  - Condon (Box-folder 19/14)
  - Coos Bay (1) (Box-folder 19/15)
  - Coos Bay (2) (Box-folder 19/16)
  - Coos County Fair (Box-folder 19/17)
  - Coos County Schools (Box-folder 19/18)
  - Coquille (Box-folder 19/19)
  - Corbett (Box-folder 19/20)
  - Cornelius (Box-folder 19/21)
  - Corvallis (Box-folder 19/22)
  - Corvallis - Oregon State University (Box-folder 19/23)
    Formerly named Oregon State College.
    Includes photographs related to OSU-based educational radio and TV station KOAC.
  - Cottage Grove (Box-folder 19/24)
  - Cougar Lane (Box-folder 19/25)
  - Country Squire Motel (Box-folder 20/1)
    Located north of Eugene.
  - Country Clerks' & Recorders' Association (Box-folder 20/2)
  - Cove Palisades State Park (Box-folder 20/3)
  - Cow Gallery (Box-folder 20/4)
    Barn converted into arthouse southeast of Oregon City.
  - Crag Rats (Box-folder 20/5)
    Mountaineering group.
  - Crane (Box-folder 20/6)
  - Crane Prairie Reservoir (Box-folder 20/7)
  - Crater Lake (Box-folder 20/8)
  - Crescent Bar Recreational Area (Box-folder 20/9)
  - Crescent Lake (Box-folder 20/10)
  - Cricket Flats (Box-folder 20/11)
    Contains image of Pine Grove Church.
  - Crooked County (Box-folder 20/12)
  - Crooked Finger Church (Box-folder 20/13)
    Located east of Mt. Angel.
  - Crooked River Canyon (Box-folder 20/14)
  - Crooked River Rodeo (Box-folder 20/15)
  - Crown Point (Box-folder 20/16)
  - Cub Scouts (Box-folder 20/17)
  - Currier's Village (Box-folder 20/18)
    Located on island on Ten Mile Lake
  - Curry Homestead (Box-folder 20/19)
  - D River (Box-folder 20/20)
  - Dairy Princesses (Box-folder 20/21)
  - Dallas (Box-folder 20/22)
  - Damascus (Box-folder 20/23)
  - Dams, Subseries 2
    - Applegate (Box-folder 20/24)
    - Bear Creek (Box-folder 20/25)
    - Bonneville (Box-folder 20/26)
    - Bull Run (Box-folder 20/27)
    - Cottage Grove (Box-folder 20/28)
    - Crooked River (Box-folder 20/29)
    - Eden Ridge (Box-folder 20/30)
    - Fall Creek (Box-folder 20/31)
    - Gold Ray (Box-folder 21/1)
    - Golden Drift (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Hells Canyon (Box-folder 21/3)
    - High Mountain Sheep (Box-folder 21/4)
      Proposed dam at Oregon-Idaho border that was not built.
    - John Day (Box-folder 21/5)
    - Lookout Point (Box-folder 21/6)
    - Lost River (Box-folder 21/7)
    - McNary (Box-folder 21/8)
      Includes photographs of the dam's 1954 dedication.
    - North Fork (Box-folder 21/9)
    - Oxbow (Box-folder 21/10)
    - Salt Caves (Box-folder 21/11)
    - Savage Rapids (Box-folder 21/12)
    - Scoggin (Box-folder 21/13)
    - The Dalles (Box-folder 21/14)
    - Tumalo Irrigation District (Box-folder 21/15)
      Diversion Dam located on Deschutes River.
    - Willow Creek (Box-folder 21/16)
    - Wells (Box-folder 21/17)
    - Wickiup (Box-folder 21/18)
    - Winchester (Box-folder 21/19)
  - Daystar Fuelohol, Inc. (Box-folder 21/20)
    Located along Highway 211 betweem Canby and Molalla.
  - Dayton (Box-folder 21/21)
  - Daughters of the American Revolution (Box-folder 21/22)
  - Dee Wright Observatory (Box-folder 21/23)
  - Deer Island (Box-folder 21/24)
  - Delake (Box-folder 21/25)
  - Demonstrations (Box-folder 21/26)
  - Demonstrations - Trojan Nuclear Plant (Box-folder 21/27)
    Includes some images of protests against the Trojan Plant held in Portland.
  - Depoe Bay (Box-folder 21/28)
  - Deschutes County (Box-folder 21/29)
  - Deschutes National Forest (Box-folder 21/30)
  - Deschutes Peak (Box-folder 21/31)
  - Deschutes River (Box-folder 21/32)
  - "Deschutes River Scenes", 1910 July (Box-folder 21/33)
    Series of photographs related to railroad building in the region, from a folder titled "Deschutes River Scenes Bldg. of Railroad 1910." Includes a photograph of deserted village Paulina.
  - Detroit (Box-folder 22/1)
  - Detroit Lake (Box-folder 22/2)
  - Devil's Lake (Box-folder 22/3)
  - Diamond Craters (Box-folder 22/4)
  - Diamond Lake (Box-folder 22/5)
  - Donald (Box-folder 22/6)
  - Donner Lake (Box-folder 22/7)
  - Douglas County (Box-folder 22/8)
  - Dover Community Church (Box-folder 22/9)
    Abandoned church located southeast of Sandy.
  - Drain (Box-folder 22/10)
  - Drewsey (Box-folder 22/11)
  - Drift Creek Falls (Box-folder 22/12)
  - Dundee (Box-folder 22/13)
  - Durham (Box-folder 22/14)
  - Dutchman's Flat (Box-folder 22/15)
  - Eagle Cap Wilderness Area (Box-folder 22/16)
  - Eagle Creek (Box-folder 22/17)
  - Eagle Creek Camp (Box-folder 22/18)
  - Eagle Creek Falls (Box-folder 22/19)
  - Eagle Creek Trail (Box-folder 22/20)
  - Eagle Creek Valley (Box-folder 22/21)
  - Eagle Point (Box-folder 22/22)
  - Eagle Scouts (Box-folder 22/23)
    See also: Oregon - Boy Scouts
  - East Eagle Mountains (Box-folder 22/24)
  - East Lake (Box-folder 22/25)
  - Eastern Oregon (Box-folder 22/26)
  - Eastside (Box-folder 22/27)
  - Echo (Box-folder 22/28)
  - Ecola State Park (Box-folder 22/29)
  - Edgefield Center (Box-folder 22/30)
  - Edgeville (Box-folder 22/31)
  - Elephant Rock (Box-folder 22/32)
  - Elgin (Box-folder 22/33)
  - Elk City (Box-folder 22/34)
  - Elk Creek (Box-folder 22/35)
  - Elk Lake (Box-folder 22/36)
  - Elks Club (Box-folder 22/37)
  - Elmira (Box-folder 22/38)
  - Emigrant Springs State Park (Box-folder 22/39)
  - Empire (Box-folder 22/40)
  - Engebersten (Box-folder 22/41)
  - Ensenada (Box-folder 22/42)
  - Enterprise (Box-folder 22/43)
  - Epilepsy League of Oregon (Box-folder 22/44)
  - Estacada (Box-folder 23/1)
  - Eugene (1) (Box-folder 23/2)
  - Eugene (2) (Box-folder 23/3)
  - Eugene (3) (Box-folder 23/4)
  - Eugene - University of Oregon (Box-folder 23/5)
  - Explorer Scouts (Box-folder 23/6)
  - Explosions (Box-folder 23/7)
    See also: Oregon - Bombs and Bombings.
  - Fairview (Box-folder 23/8)
  - Fairview Peak (Box-folder 23/9)
  - Falls City (Box-folder 23/10)
  - Fanno Creek (Box-folder 23/11)
  - Farmers Insurance Group (Box-folder 23/12)
    Images related to regional office located by Salem and Tigard-Beaverton Freeways.
  - Farmington (Box-folder 23/13)
  - Fencrest Development (Box-folder 23/14)
    Located south of Lake Oswego.
  - Fields (Box-folder 23/15)
  - Fires (1) (Box-folder 23/16)
    Photographs of fires in Oregon locations other than Portland.
    Also look under location names.
  - Fires (2) (Box-folder 23/17)
  - Fires (3) (Box-folder 23/18)
  - First Oregon Artillety Volunteer Reserves (Box-folder 24/1)
    Reenactment unit.
  - Fish Lake Remount Depot (Box-folder 24/2)
    Located in Willamette National Forest.
  - Floods (1) (Box-folder 24/3)
  - Floods (2) (Box-folder 24/4)
  - Floods (3) (Box-folder 24/5)
  - Floods - December 1964 (1) (Box-folder 24/6)
    Includes photographs taken during flood's aftermath.
  - Floods - December 1964 (2) (Box-folder 24/7)
  - Vanport Flood, 1948 May-June (Box-folder 24/8)
    Includes photographs of Vanport refugees and the immediate aftermath.
    See also: Portland - Floods - May-June 1948; Subjects - Floods - Columbia River (June 1948).
  - Vanport Flood (2), 1948 May-June (Box-folder 24/9)
  - Vanport Flood Aftermath, 1948 July - 1956 (Box-folder 24/10)
    Images of the site where Vanport stood after the flood.
  - Flora (Box-folder 24/11)
  - Florence (Box-folder 24/12)
  - Fogarty Creek State Park (Box-folder 24/13)
  - Forest Fires (1) (Box-folder 25/1)
  - Forest Fires (2) (Box-folder 25/2)
  - Forest Grove (1) (Box-folder 25/3)
  - Forest Grove (2) (Box-folder 25/4)
  - Forest Grove - Gay Nineties Festival (Box-folder 25/5)
  - Forest Grove Watershed (Box-folder 25/6)
  - Forest Hills (Box-folder 25/7)
    Located near Lake Oswego.
  - Fort Caltsop (Box-folder 25/8)
  - Fort Dalles (Box-folder 25/9)
  - Fort Rock (Box-folder 25/10)
  - Fort Stevens (Box-folder 25/11)
  - Fort Stevens (2) (Box-folder 25/12)
  - Fossil (Box-folder 25/13)
  - Franciscan Sisiters of the Eucharist (Box-folder 25/14)
    Monastery located in Columbia River Gorge.
  - Frank Farm (Box-folder 25/15)
    Property near Garden Home owned by Aaron M. Frank. Also includes a June 1933 photograph of a children's carnival held there.
  - Fremont National Forest (Box-folder 25/16)
  - Frenchglen (Box-folder 25/17)
  - Frieda (Box-folder 25/18)
  - Frog Lake (Box-folder 25/19)
  - Frog Pond (Box-folder 25/20)
  - Future Farmers of America (Box-folder 25/21)
  - Gardiner (Box-folder 25/22)
  - Garibalid (Box-folder 25/23)
  - Gates (Box-folder 25/24)
  - Gay Home (Box-folder 25/25)
    Residence of George K. Gay near Hopewell, the first brick house built in Oregon.
  - Gearhart (Box-folder 25/26)
  - Gearhart Wilderness (Box-folder 25/27)
  - Georgia-Pacific Corp. (Box-folder 26/1)
    Photographs of Georgia-Pacific plants in various Oregon places, mostly Toledo.
  - Gerlinger Forest (Box-folder 26/2)
  - Gervais (Box-folder 26/3)
  - Gifford Pinchot National Forest (Box-folder 26/4)
  - Gilbert River (Box-folder 26/5)
  - Gilchrist (Box-folder 26/6)
  - Girl Scouts (Box-folder 26/7)
    Includes Girl Scout camps.
  - Girls' State (Box-folder 26/8)
  - Glacier Lake (Box-folder 26/9)
  - Gladstone (Box-folder 26/10)
  - Glendale (Box-folder 26/11)
  - Goble (Box-folder 26/12)
  - Gods Valley (Box-folder 26/13)
  - Gold Beach (Box-folder 26/14)
  - Gold Hill (Box-folder 26/15)
  - Good Roads Movement (Box-folder 26/16)
  - Good Shepherd Lutheran Home & School for the Mentally Retarded (Box-folder 26/17)
    Located near Cornelius.
  - Goodall Home (Box-folder 26/18)
    Residence of H. B. Goodall, located between Lake Oswego and Oregon City.
  - Government Camp (Box-folder 26/19)
  - Government Island (Box-folder 26/20)
  - Grande Ronde (Box-folder 26/21)
  - Grandview Flats (Box-folder 26/22)
  - Granges (Box-folder 26/23)
  - Granite (Box-folder 26/24)
  - Granite Hill Mine (Box-folder 26/25)
    Located near Grants Pass.
  - Grant County (Box-folder 26/26)
  - Grants Pass (Box-folder 26/27)
    Includes two photographs of unnamed mines near Grants Pass.
  - Gray Butte Cemetery (Box-folder 26/28)
  - Gray Memorial Church (Box-folder 26/29)
    Located between Seaside and Astoria.
  - Green Guards (Box-folder 26/30)
  - Greenhorn (Box-folder 26/31)
  - Gresham (1) (Box-folder 27/1)
  - Gresham (2) (Box-folder 27/2)
  - Gresham - Multnomah County Fair (Box-folder 27/3)
    Photographs of pre-1970 fairs, which were held in Gresham.
  - Guerilla Units, 1942 (Box-folder 27/4)
    Photographs of armed volunteer units that assembled in World War II for defense in the event of a Japanese invasion, including a group photo of the Portland unit known as the Bushwhackers.
  - Hagg Lake (Box-folder 27/5)
  - Halfway (Box-folder 27/6)
  - Halloween Celebrations (Box-folder 27/7)
  - Halsey (Box-folder 27/8)
  - Happy Valley (Box-folder 27/9)
  - Harney County (Box-folder 27/10)
  - Harney Lake (Box-folder 27/11)
  - Harris State Park (Box-folder 27/12)
  - Harrison Hot Springs (Box-folder 27/13)
  - Hart Mountain (Box-folder 27/14)
  - Hat Rock Park (Box-folder 27/15)
  - Hayden Island (Box-folder 27/16)
  - Heceta Head (Box-folder 27/17)
  - Helvetia Community Church (Box-folder 27/18)
  - Hell Gate Canyon (Box-folder 27/19)
  - Helmick Park (Box-folder 27/20)
    Located south of Monmouth.
  - Hermiston (Box-folder 27/21)
  - Highland Games (Box-folder 27/22)
    Photograph of Highland Games held on Mt. Hood
  - Highways (Box-folder 27/23)
    Includes images related to Alsea Highway, I-205, Oregon 34, Kleinschmidt Grade, Knapps Hill Highway, McKenzie Pass Highway, and New Era Highway.
  - Highways - L. H. Gregory Roadtrips (1), circa 1919-1929 (Box-folder 27/24)
    Photographs related to automobile trips Oregonian Sports Editor Lair H. Gregory and colleagues made. Includes images of the Columbia Gorge Highway, Pacific Highway, Government Camp, and Mt. Hood.
  - Highways - L. H. Gregory Roadtrips (2), circa 1919-1929 (Box-folder 27/25)
  - Highways - Sunset Highway Construction, 1946 (Box-folder 27/26)
  - Hillman Peak (Box-folder 27/27)
  - Hillsboro (1) (Box-folder 28/1)
  - Hillsboro (2) (Box-folder 28/2)
  - Hillsboro Airport (Box-folder 28/3)
  - Hines (Box-folder 28/4)
  - Hinkle (Box-folder 28/5)
  - Hobart Butte (Box-folder 28/6)
  - Home Run Orchard (Box-folder 28/7)
    Billy Sullivan's residence near Newberg.
  - Honeyman State Park (Box-folder 28/8)
    See also: Oregon - Cleawox Lake.
  - Mt. Hood, Subseries 3
    - Aerial Tram (Box-folder 28/9)
    - Climbers (Box-folder 28/10)
    - Climbing Accidents and Rescues (1) (Box-folder 28/11)
    - Climbing Accidents and Rescues (2) (Box-folder 28/12)
    - Cloud Cap Inn (Box-folder 28/13)
      Includes conceptual drawing for a "new Cloud Cap Inn."
    - Kiwanis Camp (Box-folder 28/14)
    - Lost Lake (Box-folder 28/15)
    - Mazamas Mountain Climbing School, 1956 May 13 (Box-folder 28/16)
    - Mt. Hood Meadows (Box-folder 28/17)
    - Mt. Hood National Forest (Box-folder 28/18)
    - Peaks, Crags, Etc. (Box-folder 28/19)
    - Skiing (Box-folder 28/20)
    - Timberline Lodge (Box-folder 28/21)
    - Views (1) (Box-folder 28/22)
    - Views (2) (Box-folder 28/23)
    - Winter Sports Carnival, 1932 January (Box-folder 28/24)
    - Other Images (Box-folder 28/25)
  - Hood River (Box-folder 29/1)
  - Hood River - Columbia Gorge Hotel (Box-folder 29/2)
    Includes a photograph of Wah-Gwin-Gwin Falls in hotel's garden.
  - Hood River County (Box-folder 29/3)
  - Hood River Meadows (Box-folder 29/4)
  - Hood River Valley (Box-folder 29/5)
  - Hoodland (Box-folder 29/6)
  - Hoodoo Ski Bowl (Box-folder 29/7)
  - Horsetail Falls (Box-folder 29/8)
  - Huber (Box-folder 29/9)
  - Hug Point (Box-folder 29/10)
  - Humbug State Park (Box-folder 29/11)
  - Illinois Valley (Box-folder 29/12)
  - Imnaha (Box-folder 29/13)
  - Independence (Box-folder 29/14)
  - Independence Day Celebrations (Box-folder 29/15)
    Also known as Fourth of July Celebrations.
  - Indian Mary Park (Box-folder 29/16)
  - Ione (Box-folder 29/17)
  - Irish Lake (Box-folder 29/18)
  - Jackson County (Box-folder 29/19)
  - Jackson F. Kimball Memorial Park (Box-folder 29/20)
  - Jacksonville (Box-folder 29/21)
  - Jason Lee Mission (Box-folder 29/22)
  - Jefferson (Box-folder 29/23)
  - Mt. Jefferson (Box-folder 29/24)
  - Jefferson County (Box-folder 29/25)
  - Jefferson Park (Box-folder 29/26)
  - Jenning Lodge (Box-folder 29/27)
  - Jesuit Novitiate (Box-folder 29/28)
    Located near Sheridan.
  - Job Corps (Box-folder 29/29)
    Includes many images related to Tongue Point Job Corps.
  - John Day (Box-folder 30/1)
  - John Day Canyon (Box-folder 30/2)
    Includes images related to John Day Highhway.
  - John Day Fossil Beds (Box-folder 30/3)
  - John Day River (Box-folder 30/4)
  - Johnson City (Box-folder 30/5)
    Mobile home park located near Milwaukie.
  - Johnson Creek (Box-folder 30/6)
  - Johnson Creek Raft Races (Box-folder 30/7)
  - Johns-Manville Corp. (Box-folder 30/8)
    Lumber corporation located near Klamath Falls.
  - Jones Cemetery (Box-folder 30/9)
    Located near Sylvan.
  - Joseph - Chief Joseph Days (Box-folder 30/10)
  - Josephine County Fair (Box-folder 30/11)
  - Junior Miss Oregon (Box-folder 30/12)
  - Keating (Box-folder 30/13)
  - "Keep Oregon Green" Campaign (Box-folder 30/14)
  - Kidney Association of Oregon (Box-folder 30/15)
  - King City (Box-folder 30/16)
  - Kingsley Field (Box-folder 30/17)
  - Kinzua (Box-folder 30/18)
  - Kiwanis (Box-folder 30/19)
  - Klamath County (Box-folder 30/20)
  - Klamath Falls (Box-folder 30/21)
  - Klamath Falls Indian Agency (Box-folder 30/22)
  - Klamath Falls Ski Camp (Box-folder 30/23)
  - Klamath Indian Reservation (Box-folder 30/24)
    See also: Subjects - Indians of North America - Klamath
  - Klamath Lake (Box-folder 30/25)
  - Klamath River (Box-folder 30/26)
  - Klickitat River (Box-folder 30/27)
  - Klickitat Sawmill (Box-folder 30/28)
  - Knights of Columbus (Box-folder 30/29)
  - Knollwood Estates (Box-folder 30/30)
    Mobile home park.
  - Koosah Falls (Box-folder 30/31)
  - Krome Corp. (Box-folder 30/32)
  - La Grande (Box-folder 30/33)
  - Lafayette (Box-folder 30/34)
  - Lake County (Box-folder 30/35)
  - Lake Grove (Box-folder 30/36)
  - Lake Lytle (Box-folder 30/37)
  - Lake Oswego (1) (Box-folder 31/1)
  - Lake Oswego (2) (Box-folder 31/2)
  - Lake of the Woods (Box-folder 31/3)
  - Lakeview (Box-folder 31/4)
  - Landslides (Box-folder 31/5)
  - Lane County (Box-folder 31/6)
  - Lane County - "Views in the Siuslaw Country" (Box-folder 31/7)
    Series of photographs depicting the countryside along and near Southern Pacific Railroad from Eugene to Florence during railroad's construction. Includes images of Florence and Lake Stilacoes.
  - Larch Mountain (Box-folder 31/8)
  - Latourell Falls (Box-folder 31/9)
  - Lava Beds National Monument (Box-folder 31/10)
  - Lava Butte (Box-folder 31/11)
  - Lava Butte Crater (Box-folder 31/12)
    Loacted in Crook County.
  - Lava Caves State Park (Box-folder 31/13)
  - Lava Coast Forest (Box-folder 31/14)
  - League of Women Voters of Oregon (Box-folder 31/15)
  - Lebanon (Box-folder 31/16)
  - Lemolo Falls (Box-folder 31/17)
  - Lemolo County (Box-folder 31/18)
  - Leslie Gulch (Box-folder 31/19)
  - Lewis & Clark Campsite Park (Box-folder 31/20)
  - Lexington (Box-folder 31/21)
  - Liberal (Box-folder 31/22)
  - Lighthouse Moving, 1939; 1946 July (Box-folder 31/23)
    Series of photographs depicting the removal of a lighthouse at the mouth of the Willamette River to make way for a new house. Also includes a photograph of the lighthouse from 1939, when it was first offered for sale.
  - Lincoln City (Box-folder 31/24)
  - Lincoln County (Box-folder 31/25)
  - Link River (Box-folder 31/26)
  - Linn County (Box-folder 31/27)
  - Linnton (Box-folder 31/28)
  - Little Crater Lake (Box-folder 31/29)
  - Logan Mine (Box-folder 31/30)
  - Lolo Hot Springs (Box-folder 31/31)
  - London (Box-folder 31/32)
  - Lonerock (Box-folder 32/1)
  - Lookingglass (Box-folder 32/2)
  - Loon Lake (Box-folder 32/3)
  - Lost Creek Campsite (Box-folder 32/4)
  - Lost Forest (Box-folder 32/5)
  - Lorane (Box-folder 32/6)
  - Lyons - M & M Woodworking Plant (Box-folder 32/7)
  - Madras (Box-folder 32/8)
  - Malheur Cave (Box-folder 32/9)
  - Malheur City (Box-folder 32/10)
  - Malheur County (Box-folder 32/11)
  - Malheur Wildlife Refuge (Box-folder 32/12)
    Also known as Malhuer Bird Refuge and Malheur Game Refuge.
  - Malibu Club (Box-folder 32/13)
  - Malin Substation (Box-folder 32/14)
    Located near Klamath Falls.
  - Manhattan Beach (Box-folder 32/15)
  - Manzanita (Box-folder 32/16)
  - Marcola (Box-folder 32/17)
  - Marial (Box-folder 32/18)
  - Marion County (Box-folder 32/19)
  - Marion Lake (Box-folder 32/20)
  - Marlene Village Shopping Center (Box-folder 32/21)
  - Marmot (Box-folder 32/22)
  - Marshfield (Box-folder 32/23)
  - Marylhurst - Kerr Center for Handicapped Children (Box-folder 32/24)
  - Mayrlhurst College (Box-folder 32/25)
  - Maupin (Box-folder 32/26)
  - Maywood Park (Box-folder 32/27)
  - Mazamas (Box-folder 32/28)
  - McCabe United Methodist Church (Box-folder 32/29)
    Located southwest of McMinnville.
  - McCall Ranch (Box-folder 32/30)
    Loctaed on Crooked River between Redmond and Prineville.
  - McChord Air Base (Box-folder 32/31)
  - McIver State Park (Box-folder 32/32)
  - McKenzie River (Box-folder 32/33)
  - Mt. McLoughlin (Box-folder 32/34)
  - McMinnville (Box-folder 32/35)
  - McMinnville - Linfield College (Box-folder 32/36)
  - McNary City (Box-folder 33/1)
  - Meadowood Springs Speech Camp (Box-folder 33/2)
  - Medford (Box-folder 33/3)
  - Medical Springs (Box-folder 33/4)
  - Memaloose Island (Box-folder 33/5)
  - Memaloose Overlook (Box-folder 33/6)
  - Memorial Day Celebrations (Box-folder 33/7)
  - Menasha Co. (Box-folder 33/8)
    Photograph of tilling and filling for site near North Bend.
  - Mental Health Association of Oregon (Box-folder 33/9)
  - Merrill (Box-folder 33/10)
  - Metolius (Box-folder 33/11)
  - Metolius River (Box-folder 33/12)
  - Miller Mountain, 1940 November (Box-folder 33/13)
    Contains photograph of cabin where murdered couple Mr. and Mrs. Ira Martin had resided.
  - Millican (Box-folder 33/14)
  - Millicoma Tree Farm (Box-folder 33/15)
  - Milton-Freewater (Box-folder 33/16)
  - Milwaukie (1) (Box-folder 33/17)
  - Milwaukie (2) (Box-folder 33/18)
  - Miss Oregon (Box-folder 33/19)
    See also People Series for photographs of individual contestants.
  - Miss Teen Oregon (Box-folder 33/20)
  - Missing Persons (1) (Box-folder 33/21)
    Mostly headshots of missing people, but includes photographs related to search parties and photographs of missing people having been found.
    Includes missing people from Portland.
  - Missing Persons (2) (Box-folder 33/22)
  - Missing Persons (3) (Box-folder 33/23)
  - Mist (Box-folder 33/24)
  - Molalla (Box-folder 34/1)
  - Monmouth (Box-folder 34/2)
  - Moon Landing Tests, 1964 (Box-folder 34/3)
    Exercise in Central Oregon to simulate walking on a moonscape.
  - Moro (Box-folder 34/4)
  - Morrow County Rodeo (Box-folder 34/5)
  - Morton Loggers Jubilee (Box-folder 34/6)
  - Mt. Angel (Box-folder 34/7)
  - Mt. Hebo Air Foce Base (Box-folder 34/8)
  - Mt. Hood Hardboard and Plywood Co-Operative (Box-folder 34/9)
    Group made promises to build plant near Estacada; several members were later convicted of mail fraud.
  - Mt. View School (Box-folder 34/10)
    Located in Benton County.
  - Mountain Home United Methodist Church (Box-folder 34/11)
    Located west of Sherwood.
  - Mulino (Box-folder 34/12)
  - Multnomah (Box-folder 34/13)
  - Mulnomah County (Box-folder 34/14)
  - Multnomah Falls (Box-folder 34/15)
  - Murders (1) (Box-folder 34/16)
    Mostly photographs of crime scenes.
    Includes Portland murders.
    Also look under individual case names.
  - Murders (2) (Box-folder 34/17)
  - Murphy (Box-folder 34/18)
  - Myrtle Creek (Box-folder 34/19)
  - Mystery House (Box-folder 34/20)
    Located near Gold Hill.
  - Naturalization Ceremonies (Box-folder 34/21)
  - Neah-Kah-Nie (Box-folder 34/22)
  - Nelscott (Box-folder 34/23)
  - Netarts Bay (Box-folder 34/24)
    Includes a photograph of the community of Netarts.
  - Newberg (Box-folder 34/25)
  - Newbridge (Box-folder 34/26)
  - Newport (Box-folder 35/1)
    Includes images of Nye Beach and Jumpoff Joe.
  - North Bend (Box-folder 35/2)
  - North Pacific Co-Operative Creameries (Box-folder 35/3)
  - North Plains (Box-folder 35/4)
  - Nyssa (Box-folder 35/5)
  - Oak Grove (Box-folder 35/6)
  - Oak Grove Hydroelectric Plant (Box-folder 35/7)
  - Oceanlake (Box-folder 35/8)
  - Oceanside (Box-folder 35/9)
  - Old Oregon Museum (Box-folder 35/10)
  - Optimist Club Camp (Box-folder 35/11)
  - Oregon Butter & Ice Cream Makers' Association (Box-folder 35/12)
  - Oregon Caves (Box-folder 35/13)
  - Oregon City (Box-folder 35/14)
  - Oregon Congress of Parents & Teachers (Box-folder 35/15)
  - Oregon Country Fair, 1976 June (Box-folder 35/16)
    Fair was held near Elmira.
  - Oregon Federation of Women's Clubs (Box-folder 35/17)